字幕由SSK字幕组倾情译制
新浪微博@SSK字幕组 官网：www.sskzmz.com
字幕仅供学习，勿用于商
转载请注明出处，版权归片方所有
翻译｜Dark Paradise　林白一　JUNO　yuli
校对｜Luke　　特效｜BUNNY　　压制｜fsffsfs　　总监｜Luke
字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者
嘿 伙计
Hey, my man, t., what's going on dawg?
- 你好  - 你好
- What's up, what's up.  - How you doing?
- 你需要什么  - 你能帮帮我吗 伙计
- What you need?  - Can you help me out, man?
不 兄弟 我帮不了你
No, I can't do it, bro. You gotta keep moving. I can't do it.
- 求你了 伙计  - 我帮不了你
- Come on, man.  - Keep it movin'.
- 孩子  - 让一下 伙计
- Boy.  - Step aside, man.
- 你好啊  - 你怎么样
- How you doing?  - What's good with you?
我很好 伙计 还是像往常一样在这儿忙活着
I'm all right, man. I'm out here handling business as usual.
听着 伙计 我没有不尊重你的意思
Look, man, I don't mean no disrespect or nothing to you,
我只是问问能不能给我点
I'm just trying to see if I can get a little...
给不了你 伙计 你知道现在几点吗
you can't get nothing, man. You know what time it is, bruh?
我一直帮你盯着警察
I keep looking out for you, man.
就一丁点 行吗
Just a little something, man?
一丁点你也得花钱买啊
All my something cost a little something, man.
没钱就赶紧走人吧大兄弟
If he ain't got it get to stepping, nigga.
你知道现在几点了吗 我不想老是自说自话
You know what time it is? I don't feel like repeating myself.
嘿 你知道我的伙计对吗 胡安
Hey, you know you my man, right Juan?
这个兄弟
This nigga...
你傻了么 伙计
Yo. Trippin', man.
看你能不能为我做点事
See-see-see-see if you can do something here for me...
妈的我刚刚怎么跟你说的 东西给我
What the fuck I just told you? Let me get this shit!
给我滚开
Nigga, get the fuck out of here, man.
滚
Go on!
噢 看着那个人 伙计
Oh, get that nigga, man.
- 你怎么样  - 我很好 很好
- What's up?  - I'm good, good.
- 我就在这 你知道的  - 是的
- I'm just out here, you know.  - Yeah.
平常的一天
Regular day.
这里很隐蔽 你需要钱我就找人拿钱
It's in the cut. Everybody cleaned out if you need anything.
- 生意还好吗  - 是的 还好
- Business good?  - Yeah it's good.
- 我给你带了点  - 不 你先保管好
- I got something for you...  - no, no. Hold onto that.
周末整理好给我
Empty the register on the weekend.
好的 没问题
All right, no problem, son.
你妈现在怎么样了
How's your mom feeling now?
噢 她挺好 她很好
Oh, she doing good. She doing excellent.
- 好多了  - 好多了
- Better?  - She doing better.
你知道的
You know.
我一直在为她祈祷 伙计
She's in my prayers, man.
非常感谢
Most naturally. Thank you.
谢谢你给我的机会 我会努力的
Thanks for the opportunity. I'm out here.
- 抓住他  - 你过来
- Get him!  - Get your ass right here.
- 抓住他  - 你为什么总跑
- Get him!  - Why you always runnin'?
别跑啊死基佬
Goin' around with that faggot ass, bro!
- 还能不能抓住他了  - 揍他
- Ain't gonna catch him!  - Kick his ass!
- 那就追啊 伙计  - 抓住他
- Run, then, nigga!  - Get his gay ass!
- 来啊 兄弟  - 抓住他
- Come on, bro!  - Catch that nigga!
去后面
Go around the back.
小家伙 你在这干嘛呢
What you doin' in here, li'l man?
嗯哼
Huh?
你不和陌生人说话吗
You don't talk to strangers?
好吧 没事了
A'ight. It's cool.
没事了
We cool.
听着
Listen...
我要去弄点吃的
I'm about to go get something to eat.
要不要和我一起去
You're welcome to join me if you want.
我可以从前门走吗
It's okay if I take the front door?
嗯哼
Hmm?
来吧
Come on now.
外面很好
Can't be no worse out here.
一. 小不点
你不打算告诉我你的名字了吗
You not gonna tell me what yo' name is?
那你住在哪呢
How 'bout where you live?
我得把你送回去 小家伙
I got to get you home, little man.
不能让你在毒窝里乱跑
Can't have you just runnin' around these dope holes.
你明白吗
You understand?
嘿 我的错
Hey, hey, hey, my bad.
噢 小伙子 你知道我不会这么对你的
Oh man, you know I ain't gonna do you like that.
我道歉 好吗
Hey man, I apologize, all right?
我只是想让你说句话
I'm just trying to get you to say something.
嘿
Hey...
我道歉
I apologize.
好了
All right.
你现在这样好了
You all right now...
但我女朋友会过来找你
...until my girl come get you, though.
她会让你说话的
She gonna make you talk.
我一会回来
Be right back.
- 特瑞莎  - 嘿 宝贝
- Teresa!  - Hey, baby.
我在毒窝发现了这个小男孩
I found this little boy in a dope spot.
在哪里发现的
Found a little boy in a what?
那里没人吸毒
Wasn't no crack heads up in there.
他自己在那儿
He by himself.
但是他不愿意说话 你能不能
He ain't talking though, so why don't you see
让他说几句话
if you can get him to say something.
- 真的  - 去跟他说几句
- Really?  - Just go talk to him.
去吧
Just go talk to him.
真是难以置信
I cannot believe you.
- 我爱你  - 是谁能让你这么做
- Love you.  - Who would you do something like this?
你不说话但你可挺能吃
You don't talk much but you damn sure can eat.
没关系 宝贝
That's all right, baby.
等你吃好喝好了再说话也不迟
You ain't got to talk 'til you get good and ready.
我叫奇伦
My name is chiron.
大家都叫我小不点
People call me little.
好的 小不点
All right then, little.
那我就叫你的名字了
Well im'ma call you by your name, then.
你住在哪儿 奇伦
Where you from, chiron?
自由城[迈阿密的一个街区]
Liberty city.
你和妈妈一起生活
You live with your mama?
是的
Yes.
你爸爸呢
What about your daddy?
没事
That's all right.
你想让我们把你带回家吗
You want us to take you home, then,
在你吃完饭之后
after you get finished eating your food?
你得告诉我们你住在哪儿 孩子
Yeah, you gotta tell us where you live, bruh.
不
No...
好吧
Okay.
你今晚可以留在这里
You can stay here tonight.
特瑞莎
Teresa...
你想这样吗
Would you like that?
好
Okay.
怎么回事
What happened?
怎么了 奇伦
What happened, chiron?
你昨晚怎么没回家呢
Why you didn't come home like you supposed to?
你是谁
And who is you?
无名氏
Nobody.
我昨天看见他的
I found him yesterday.
在十五号街的一个窝点
Found him in a hole on 15th.
是的 那一间
Yeah. That one.
几个男孩对他穷追不舍
Some boys chased him in the cut.
他吓坏了
He's scared more than anything.
直到今天早上他才告诉我住哪
He wouldn't tell me where he lived 'til this morning.
好吧 谢谢你照顾他
Well, thanks for seeing to him.
通常他能自己照顾自己
He usually can take care of hisself...
他是可以 可是
...he good that way, but...
小家伙
Little man.
你是我的宝贝 奇伦 你知道吗
You a real damn prize, chiron, you know that?
该回家的时候就要回家
You got'sta come home when you meant to come home.
听到了吗
You hear?
没事了 宝贝
That's all right, baby.
没事了
That's all right.
妈妈很开心你回来了
Mama just glad you're home.
不
Nuh-uh.
你不能看电视
TV privilege is revoked.
找点书看看
Find something for you to read.
球在哪
Where the ball at?
我得不到球
I don't got the ball no more!
嘿 小不点
Hey, little!
你好啊
Wassup, man?
嘿 凯文
Hey, Kevin.
你为什么要走
Why'd you leave?
我不知道
I don't know.
是的 玩一会就无聊了
Yeah, it get borin' after a while.
怎么了
What?
流血了吗
Is it bleedin'?
怎么了
What?
你很有趣 伙计
You funny, man.
你为什么这么说
Why you say that?
你就是有趣
You just is, that's all.
你为什么老是被欺负 伙计
Why do you always let people pick on you, man?
你什么意思
What you mean?
你老是让他们欺负你
You always letting them pick on you.
那我该怎么办
So what I gotta do?
你应该
All you gotta do
向他们展示你并不软弱
is show these niggas you ain't soft.
但我不软弱
But I ain't soft.
我知道 我知道
I know, I know.
但如果他们不知道就毫无意义
But it don't mean nothing if they don't know it.
来吧
Come on.
你想让那些傻瓜整天欺负你吗
You want these fools to pick on you every day?
看到了吗 小不点
See little?
我知道你不软弱
I knew you wasn't soft.
来吧 伙计
Come on, man.
把头伸过来
Give me your head.
头靠在我手上
Let your head rest in my hand.
放松
Relax.
我抓着你 我保证
I got you. I promise.
我不会放手的
I'm not going to let you go.
嘿 伙计 我抓着你
Hey man, I got you.
就是这样
There you go.
十秒钟
Ten seconds.
感受到了吗
Feel that right there?
你处在世界中心 伙计
You're in the middle of the world, man.
做得好
That's good.
就像这样
Do like this.
看看你
Look at you.
再敏捷一点
More athletic.
就这样
There you go.
是的 我认为你准备好了
Yeah. I think you ready.
我认为你会游泳了
I think we got a swimmer.
你想试试吗 你准备好了吗
You wanna try? You ready to swim?
来吧
Go.
好样的 伙计
Yeah, man!
好样的
Yeah!
我跟你说 伙计
Let me tell you something, man.
黑人无处不在
There are black people everywhere.
记住这一点 好吗
You remember that, okay?
这个世界上
No place you can go in the world
到处都有黑人的踪影
ain't got no black people.
我们是这个星球上最早诞生的人类
We was the first ones on this planet.
我来这里很久了
I been here a long time...
但我来自古巴
...but I'm from Cuba.
古巴有很多黑人
Lotta black folks in Cuba,
但你在这里不知道这些
but you wouldn't know it from being here, though.
我当时也是个虎头虎脑的小个子 伙计
I was a wild li'l shorty, man.
像你一样
Just like you.
在月光下光着脚奔跑
Runnin' around with no shoes on when the moon was out.
有一次
This one time...
我路过一位奶奶
I run by this old... This old lady.
我在跑 一直跑
I was runnin', hollerin'...
像一个傻孩子
...and cuttin' a fool, boy.
老奶奶截下我
This old lady, she stopped me.
她说
She said...
奔跑
..."running around...
追逐光亮的方向
...catching up all that light.
在月光下
In moonlight...
黑人男孩是蓝色的
...black boys look blue.
你是蓝色的
You blue.
所以我以后就叫你
That's what I gon' call you.
蓝
Blue."
那你的名字叫蓝吗
So your name blue?
不
Nah.
有些时候你得自己决定你要做什么
At some point you gotta decide for yourself who you gonna be.
没人能替你做决定
Can't let nobody make that decision for you.
你喜欢游泳吗 伙计
How you like swimming, man?
这么喜欢啊
That much, huh?
嘿 等下 等下
Hey, hold up, hold up.
选一个
Pick one.
啊
Aah...
哈哈 选得好
Ha ha. Good choice.
把它放你口袋
Put it in your pocket.
嘿
Hey.
等一下 喂
Yo, hold up. Whoa, whoa, hey...
来吧
come on.
你还好吗 小不点
What's going on, little man?
来吧
Come on!
伙计 他们和我的一样
Man, they're all the same as mine.
至少我的看起来不像弗莱迪・克鲁格
At least mine don't look like Freddy kruger.
你的丑爆了
Yours ugly as hell.
我的一点也不丑
Mine don't look like no peanut.
告诉你 我的一点也不丑
Telling you, mine does not look like no peanut.
谁让他进来的
Who let his ass in?
有人和你一起吗
Somebody with you?
伙计 我发誓它锁上了
Man, I swear it was locked.
伙计 没犯规 没犯规
Man, ain't no foul. Ain't no foul.
怎么了
S'up?!
你死定了 打你的脸
You're dead, baby! Right in your face!
我是花了钱 但这不是我要买的啊
It's what I paid for. It ain't what I bought.
伙计 这已经是高级货了
Man, that's grade a quality.
你还想要我怎么样
What else you want me to do?
伙计 这更像是下等货
Nigga, this shit look more like grade c.
伙计 这话我可不爱听
Man, look. I ain't goin' with that, man!
我要把钱要回来
I want my money back.
什么 不接受退款 伙计
What?! Ain't no refund, man.
收好它 伙计 走吧
Just stuff it, man. Keep movin'. Go on.
你还好吗
Yo what's up? You all right?
我以为你去度假了呢
Thought you was on vacation or some shit.
拜托 伙计 这里哪有假期
Come on, man. No vacation out here.
我得工作啊
I know the work, you know that.
去瑞士或别的地方
Going to Switzerland or some shit.
瑞士 伙计
Switzerland, man.
可能会去巴西吧 你知道的 和两个好看的姑娘
Maybe Brazil, you know, with two bad bitches.
小花生干得怎么样
How peanut working out?
他很好 我能搞定他
Peanut good, man. I got him at in check.
他在他该在的地方 你知道
He's staying in his place, you know.
他们在吸毒吗
They basin'?
当然不是了 你知道我不会容许这种事情发生
Hell no, you know I ain't gonna let that go down.
你现在都让人在这里点火了吗
Yo, nigga, you lettin' people light up at the spot, now?
- 噢 不  - 妈的
- Hell no.  - The f...
你知道我不会容许这种事情发生
come on, you know I ain't gonna let that happen, man.
妈的
The fuck, man.
伙计 怎么回事
Yo nigga, what's up?
嘿 嘿 没什么 伙计
Hey, hey, it's all good, man.
- 你他妈在干嘛  - 没事 胡安
- The fuck you doing?  - It's all good, Juan.
妈的
Fuck.
- 一切都好  - 滚出来
- It's all good...  - get out the fucking car!
- 冷静点 伙计  - 闭嘴
- Calm down, man.  - Shut the fuck up.
你有毛病吗
What's wrong with you?
你以为你是谁
Who the hell you think you is?
给我滚远点
Bitch, get the fuck out of here.
什么 所以你要抚养我儿子吗
What, so you gon' raise my son now?
你要抚养我儿子吗
You gon' raise my son?
- 我想的没错  - 我不养你养吗
- Yeah... that's what I thought.  - You gon' raise him?
你要接着卖给我毒品
You gon' keep sellin' me rocks?
混蛋
Motherfucker.
别给我摆出一副爱理不理的样子
Don't give me that "You gotta get it from somewhere" Shit, nigga.
我就要从你这里买
I'm gettin' it from you.
但你还会抚养我儿子 不是吗
But you gon' raise my son though, right?
你看过他走路的样子吗 胡安
You ever see the way he walk, Juan?
你注意你说的话
You watch your damn mouth.
你要告诉他为什么别的孩子都欺负他吗
You gon' tell him why the other boys kick his ass all the time?
你要告诉他吗
You gon' tell him?
你个垃圾
You ain't shit.
走 我们走
Come on! Let's go!
你们瞅啥
The fuck y'all lookin' at?
特瑞莎
Teresa.
你的小男朋友来了
Your boyfriend's here.
孩子
Boy.
今天要跟我说话吗
You talking to me today?
好吧
Okay.
没关系
That's alright.
反正我也不想跟你说话
I don't wanna talk to you, anyway.
你知道她喜欢你 是吧
You know she got a crush on you, right?
你还好吗
You all right?
你一路走过来的吗
You walk all the way here?
好吧
All right.
首先 重中之重 你不能坐在这个位置
First things first. You can't sit at my table like that.
你不能背对着门坐 起来
You can't sit with your back to the door, come on.
如果有人悄悄靠近你 你会浑然不知
Ain't gonna know if somebody creepin' up on you.
好了 看到了吗
All right, see that?
现在一切尽收眼底
Now you can see everything.
想什么呢
What's over there?
我昨晚看见你妈妈了
I saw your mama last night.
我讨厌她
I hate her.
嗯
Hmm.
嗯 我猜你也是
Yeah, I bet you do.
我也不喜欢我妈妈
I hated my mom, too.
尽管我现在很想她
I miss her like hell now though.
这就是对这件事我要说的
That's all I'm gon' say about that.
谢谢
Thank you.
什么是基佬
What's a faggot?
基佬是
A faggot is...
是一个侮辱同性恋的词
...A word used to make gay people feel bad.
- 我是基佬吗  - 不
- Am I a faggot?  - No.
不是
No.
你可以是同性恋 但你不能让别人叫你基佬
You can be gay, but you gotta let nobody call you no faggot.
我是说 除非
I mean, unless...
我怎么知道我是不是
How do I know?
你会知道的
You just do.
我觉得
I think.
到时候你就知道了
You'll know when you know.
嘿
Hey...
你现在还不会知道 好吗
You ain't gotta know right now, all right?
现在还不会
Not yet.
你贩毒吗
Do you sell drugs?
嗯
Yeah.
那我妈妈
And my mama...
她是不是吸毒
...she do drugs, right?
嗯
Yeah.
好 脱氧核糖核酸
Okay, deoxyribonucleic acid.
很长的一个词 对不对
Long word, right?
好 它本质上就是基因
All right, it's basically genes.
我知道你们还不知道这是什么意思
I know y'all don't know what that means
但是请先认真听
but just hang with me for a second.
本质上这个长
So it's basically this long...
奇伦 你需要什么吗
chiron, you need something?
他忘了换卫生棉
Hey yo, that nigga forgot to change his tampon.
抱歉 皮尔斯老师
I'm sorry, Mr. Pierce.
他今天有女性生理问题
He just having woman problems today.
- 对不对 小不点  - 好了 特雷尔 够了
- Ain't that right, little?  - All right, Terrell, that's enough.
不 小不点可觉得不够
Nah, can't be enough for little..
你要多少 小不点
How much you need, little?
- 不要那样叫我  - 好了 特雷尔 到此为止
- Don't call me that!  - All right Terrell, that's it.
你想干嘛 奇伦 看我削你
Hey, what you gonna do, chiron? I'll fuck you up.
特雷尔 出去
Hey yo, Terrell, out!
拜托 你怎么了
Come on, man. What's wrong with you?
我们讲到哪了
Where were we?
脱氧核糖核酸本质上是一个很长的模型
DNA is basically this long model...
等我收拾你 小不点
Im'ma be waitin' for your ass, little.
别害怕 奇伦
Come on, chiron.
奇伦 怎么了 兄弟
Chiron, what's up, man?
天呐 你在发什么呆 哥们
Damn, nigga. You straight spaced, dawg.
学校人都走完了 你不回家吗
Yo, school been out. You ain't going home?
呃
Uh...
你在这干嘛
What you doin' here?
留校 兄弟
Detention, man.
埃姆斯逮到我在楼梯间打炮
Aimes caught me with this trick in the stairway.
- 真倒霉  - 是啊
- Damn.  - Yeah.
跟谁
With who?
你还真是个八婆 兄弟
Damn, you nosey, nigga.
- 我的错  - 不是 我开玩笑的
- My bad...  - no, I'm playing, yo.
听着 我只是想快点做完 你知道吗
Look, I wanted some quick head you know,
但是那个小妞老是说“用力 凯文”
but this chick all like "Hit that shit, Kevin.
“用你的大鸡巴操我”
Hit it with that big dick."
这么夸我有意思么
Why she got to compliment a nigga for?
所以我就说“好吧 我们来吧” 你知道吗
So I'm like "A'ight. Shit. We can do this", you know?
然后我就开始大力干她
So I started banging her back out, dawg.
我是说大力干她
I'm talking I'm banging her back out.
但是她大吼大叫
She went and made all this fucking noise though.
然后埃姆斯就进来了 弄得跟警察一样
So aimes come in, acted all five-o and shit,
差点让我停学 哥们
almost had my ass suspended, dawg.
虽然我供认不讳
I talked it out, though.
但是我告诉他我们是青梅竹马 类似的话
I told him we was like childhood sweethearts and all of that,
所以我只被留校 还不错
so I just got detention, it's cool.
- 不错  - 这件事只有我们两个人知道 对吧
- Cool.  - That stay between us, a'ight?
对
Yeah.
我知道你会守口如瓶的 兄弟
I know you can keep a secret, dawg.
真心话 好了 我要走了
Real talk though, I gotta go, a'ight,
在那个傻逼改变注意之前
before this fool change his mind.
好的 小凯
All right, kev.
回见 小黑
See you, black.
二. 奇伦
- 嘿 妈妈  - 你今晚不能待在这儿
- Hey, mama.  - Uh-uh. You cannot be here tonight.
我有客人要来
I got company coming.
找个能收留你的地方吧
Find somewhere for you to be.
好了
All right...
我喝水 这杯杜松子酒给你
...water for me... And a little gin for you.
拜托
Boy please.
我知道胡安以前经常给你酒喝
I know Juan used to give you that gin.
但是现在他不在了 小不点
But we ain't doing that up in here, shorty.
你不觉得我的笑话很好笑吗
You don't think my joke was funny?
怎么了
What's wrong?
没事
Nothing.
我没事
I'm good.
才怪
No.
我知道没事是什么样 你现在一点都不好
I've seen good and you ain't it.
在我家不要再把头低着了
Stop putting your head down in my house.
你知道我的规矩
You know my rule.
这间房子里都是爱和骄傲
It's all love and all pride in this house.
懂我的意思吗
You feel me?
我听不见你说话
I can't hear you.
懂我的意思吗
Do you feel me?
懂
Yeah.
- 好  - 我懂你的意思
- Okay.  - I feel you.
好的
All right.
谢谢你收留我
Thank you for this.
孩子 别这样
Boy, please,
你知道如果需要你随时都可以待在这儿 好吗
you know you can stay here any time you need to, okay?
随时
Any time.
嗯
Yeah.
谢谢你 特瑞莎 真的感谢
Thank you, Teresa. I mean it.
如果你还想待在这儿
Now, if you gon' stay here, though,
你就得学会如何
you gonna have to learn how to make a bed
铺好床 孩子
better than this, boy.
- 什么  - 什么
- What?  - What you mean, "What"?
把那个给我 不是你这样铺床的
Give me that. That ain't how you make up no bed.
你肯定觉得自己很狡猾
You think you slick, too.
自己做错了
You know, do it all wrong
这样特瑞莎就可以来帮你弄好
so Teresa can come over here and do it right.
我知道你打什么鬼主意
I know what you doing.
你和胡安
Oof, you and Juan.
你们两个真不愧是好兄弟
Y'all two, thick as thieves.
那个给我
Give me that.
好了
All right.
还需要我做什么吗 亲爱的
Do you need anything else from me, sweetheart?
呃 没了 我很好
Uh, no, I'm good.
好吧
Okay.
好吧 我明天早上叫醒你
All right, I'm gonna wake you up in the morning.
你好吗 小黑
You good, black?
奇伦
Chiron!
- 嘿 宝贝  - 嘿 妈妈
- Hey! Hey, baby!  - Hey, mama.
你昨晚去哪儿了
Where'd you go last night?
什么
What?
怎么了
Why?
我是不是你妈妈
I'm yo' mama, ain't I?
为什么你不回家 孩子
Why you ain't just come home later, boy?
你让我一直担心你
You had me worried about you.
我猜你长大了
I guess you getting grown.
我不能一直把你留在我身边
I can't be keeping up with you all the time.
宝贝 特瑞莎怎么样
Anyway baby, how Teresa doing?
自从葬礼之后 我就没见过她
I ain't seen her since the funeral.
妈妈把自己锁在门外了
Listen, mama locked herself out the door, yeah?
你来开下门吧
Can you come let her in?
快点 宝贝
Come on, baby.
让我进去吧 宝贝
Let me in, baby.
宝贝 求你了
Baby, come on.
我以为你说过
I thought you said...
妈妈 我以为
mama, I thought you...
等一下 妈妈 妈妈
wait, mama... mama!
我需要钱
I need some money.
用来干什么
For what?
这是我的事
That's my business.
你没资格过问
Don't you ask me no shit like that.
- 我没有钱  - 不不 不要骗我 孩子
- I don't have no money...  - no, no. Don't lie to me, boy.
我是你妈妈
I'm your mama.
那个特瑞莎跟你一点关系都没有
That bitch over there ain't no kin of you.
我才是你的亲人 知道吗
I'm your blood, remember?
我现在感觉很不好
Now I ain't feeling good.
我需要解脱
I need something to help me out.
求你了 宝贝
Come on, baby.
我去哪儿找钱啊
Where I'm supposed to get money from?
什么
What?
特瑞莎难道没给你点钱吗
Teresa ain't give you nothing, huh?
她怎么可能没给你揣点钱
Your li'l play-play mama ain't put something in your hand?
把钱给我
Give me that damn money, chiron.
把钱给我 把钱给我
Give me the damn money! Give me the damn money!
我真的没钱
I don't have no money!
- 妈妈 求你了  - 把钱给我
- Mama, come on...  - give me the damn money!
好了 好了
All right! All right!
把钱给我
Give me the damn money.
给你
Here, man.
这就对了
Yes. That is what I thought.
我对她还真是了解
I know that bitch like a hooker know her trick.
你是我的孩子 好吗
You my child, okay?
告诉她最好不要忘了
And tell that bitch she better not forget it.
接着去上学
Go on to school.
你没迟到吗
Ain't you late?
所以现在你可以知道白血球减少
So you can see how a lack of white blood cells
对人体很危险 对不对
can be dangerous to the human body, right?
好 有人能解释一下 如果没有足够的白血球
Okay, can anybody explain what will happen to the body
人体会有什么反应吗
if there's not enough white blood cells?
如果没人回答问题
Ain't nobody's leaving this classroom
就不下课
until I get a response.
相信我 这个问题你知道比我知道要更重要
This is more important for you than it is for me, trust me.
嘿 小不点
Hey yo, little!
走这么快去哪
Where you going to so fast, huh?
- 我要回家  - 什么
- I'm going home.  - Huh?
我跟你说了 我要回家
Man, I told you. I'm going home!
你觉得我们傻吗 你住在那边
You think we stupid? You live over there, nigga.
哦 不对 他要去特瑞莎家
Oh no, he going to Teresa house.
特瑞莎 那不是胡安的女朋友吗
Teresa? That's Juan lady, ain't it?
是哦 她长得可真是漂亮呢
Oh yeah. She fine as hell.
- 胡安才刚死没多久  - 就是啊
- Juan been dead a minute, though.  - You right.
天哪 她免费口交吗
Hell, she give free head?
还是她像宝拉那样收费
Or does she charge like Paula?
宝拉现在便宜了
Hell, Paula getting cheap though.
口气硬口活也硬
Talkin' like a rock can get your rock sucked!
你什么意思
Nigga, what was that?!
放开我
Get off me, dawg.
我不搞同性恋
Now I ain't with that gay shit,
但是如果你敢惹我
but if you fuck with me
我能让你的菊花欲罢不能
I'll give your ass more than you can handle.
让你哭着找你的瘾君子老母
Have you runnin' to your crackhead-ass mama.
我的天呐
My nigga!
- 操你妈的  - 你说什么
- Fuck y'all niggas!  - What'd you say?!
有种再说一遍 我保证不打死你
Say that shit again dog, I swear.
不敢了
Whatever, man.
那就好 你最好给我识相点
A'ight, you better stay your ass right there
别自讨苦吃
if you know what's good for you.
为什么你的牛仔裤这么紧
Yo, why your jeans so tight?
唷 彼佐 你看这个人的牛仔裤
Yo, pizzo, you see these nigga's jeans be?
你看到了吗
You see that shit?
黑蛋快被挤爆了吧
Nigga nuts must be chokin' in those!
- 说的是实话  - 好了 祝你好梦 小不点
- Real talk!  - A'ight, night little.
回头见了
See your ass later.
你是在等我吗
You was waitin' for me?
嗯 很高兴见到你
Well, nice to see you too.
你来这儿干什么 兄弟
What you doing out here, man?
你来这儿干什么
What you doing out here?
这是我抽烟的地儿 哥们
This is my smoker habitat, nigga.
怎么 你也出来抽烟
Oh what, you smoke out here too?
差不多吧
Something like that...
你不吸烟
Nah, you don't smoke.
装啥
Why you pretending?
在我面前装蒜吗 小黑
Trying to put on a show for me, black?
你为什么总是这么叫我
Why you always calling me that?
- 什么 小黑  - 嗯 小黑
- What, black?  - Yeah, black.
这是我给你取的昵称 你不喜欢吗
That's my nickname for you. You don't like it?
不是 只不过
No, it's just...
什么人才会
...what kind of dude goes around
到处给别人取昵称啊
giving other dudes nicknames?
就是我这种刚坐下来
The kind of dude what just sat down
来给你点上雪茄的人 兄弟
and is about to put you onto this blunt, nigga.
耶
Yeah.
你喜欢水吗
You like the water?
我可以给你点“火”
I can introduce you to some "Fiyah."
试一下 兄弟 又不会咬你
Come on, nigga. It ain't gonna bite you.
天哪 我还不知道你抽烟是这个样子
Damn, I didn't know you smoked like that.
我妈妈在家里什么都抽
My mom leaves all types of shit around.
微风让我感觉很舒服 哥们
That breeze feel good as hell man.
确实是这样
Yeah, it do.
有时候在我们住的街道附近
Sometimes round the way, where we live...
你都能感觉到同样的风
...you can catch that same breeze.
穿过住宅区 好像所有的事
It just come through the hood and it's like everything stop
都暂时停下来了
for a second...
因为所有人都想感受一下
...'cause everyone just wanna feel it.
一切都变得安静 你知道吗
Everything just gets quiet, you know?
你唯一能听见的就是自己的心跳
And it's like all you can hear is your own heartbeat.
是吗
Right?
对
Yeah...
感觉真的很好 兄弟
Feel so good, man.
真的很好
So good...
见鬼 让人想哭
Hell, shit make you wanna cry, feel so good.
你哭了
You cry?
没有
Nah.
只是想哭
Makes me want to.
你为什么哭
What you cry about?
有时候我会哭个不停
Shit, I cry so much sometimes
感觉自己都快变成水做的了
I feel like I'm gon' just turn into drops.
感觉自己可以一头扎进水里 是吗
Think you can roll out into the water, right?
扎进水里 就像所有人都想
Roll out into the water like all these other motherfuckers
把麻烦事都抛在脑后
around here trying to drown they sorrows.
你为什么这么说
Why you say that?
我听出你是这个意思 兄弟
I'm just listening to you, nigga.
听起来像是你想要做的事
Sound like something you wanna do.
我想做很多讲不通的事
I wanna do a lot of things that don't make sense.
我没有说讲不通啊
I didn't say it don't make sense.
但是和我说说 有什么事
But tell me, like-like what?
是你觉得讲不通的
Like what "Lot of things"?
天哪
Damn dog...
你个八婆
...you nosey.
奇伦现在也会骂人了
Chiron cursing now, huh?
- 你和我闹呢  - 随便你怎么说 哥们
- You trying to get smart with me?  - Whatever, man.
你和我耍小聪明呢 奇伦
Nah, you trying to get smart with me, huh chiron?
你和我耍小聪明呢
Yeah, you trying to get smart with me, huh.
抱歉
I'm sorry...
抱什么歉
What you gotta be sorry for?
你之前没做过这样的事吧
You ain't never done nothing like that before, huh?
谢谢你载我回来 哥们
Thanks for the ride, man.
不客气 小黑
No problem, black.
回见
I'll see you around.
好
Yeah...
回见
...see you around.
过来 宝贝
Come here, baby.
过来
Come here.
你不再爱我了
You don't love me no more...
你不再爱我了啊
你是我的唯一
You're my only.
我也是你的唯一
I'm your only.
你是我的唯一
You're my only...
- 你好啊 凯文  - 特雷尔 别来无恙
- Yo, what's up, kev?  - Terrell, what's up man?
嘿 上学真没意思
Hey, you know a nigga don't see school no more.
是啊 你说得对
No, I hear you, man.
以前的午餐太难吃了
Lunch used to be the shit, though.
呐 食物本来就没好过
Nah, the food wasn't never good.
老兄 我没在说食物
Man, I ain't talkin' 'bout the food.
但是周五的披萨真是烂到爆
But that Friday pizza was the shit.
是啊 我懂你
Yeah, I feel you.
但你还是否记得在中学的时候
Nah, but you remember in middle school,
我们玩的游戏
that game we used to play?
“一拳打倒/躺在地下”
"Knock down/stay down"?
是哟 我是玩那个游戏的一把好手
Yeah yo, my crazy ass was the king of that shit.
是 我记得
Yeah I remember. Yo!
你记得被你虐翻了的那个白人小孩么
You remember that white kid you fucked up?
古巴佬是么 马里西奥还是什么
Cuban cat, right? Mauricio or something?
对 你简直把他虐惨了
Oh yeah! Yo, you fucked that kid's face up!
从此以后我们可都叫你泰森
We was calling you Tyson after that shit.
是啊
Yeah.
但是 啊
Yo, but, uh...
现在大家都不这么玩了
...niggas don't do that shit no more.
有点可惜
I mean... you know...
你想说什么
What you sayin'?
我说的是 如果我选中一个人
I'm sayin' is, if I point a nigga out...
你会把他打趴下吗
...is you gonna knock his ass down?
这就是游戏规则呀
That's the game, ain't it?
你问我敢不敢打人 如果我打了责任就在你
You dare me to swing on him and if I do, it's on you.
好啊 好啊 凯文
A'ight. A'ight kev.
来看看谁今天要被打趴下咯
Let me see who ass gettin' dropped today.
别再喝这个黏糊糊的果汁了
Don't be drinking none of this gummy juice.
它会要了你的命
Shit'll kill you.
哟 凯文
Yo, kev.
打他
Hit that nigga.
打他 凯文
Hit that nigga, kev.
嘿 打那个基佬
Yeah, hit his faggot ass!
你等啥呢 快上
The fuck you waitin' on? Do it! Come on.
来吧
Let's go.
你感觉如何 奇伦
How you like that, chiron?
哟 我觉得他还想来一下
Yo, I think he want another.
再给他一下 快
Another one. Do it.
给他一拳
Give it to him.
你最好别起来
Don't you get up, bruh.
躺下
You stay down!
如果他起来 再把他打倒
Yeah if he get back up, knock his faggot ass back down.
- 奇伦 躺下  - 他起来了
- Chiron, stay down!  - He got up.
求你了老兄
Come on, man.
躺下
Stay down.
再来一拳
Do it again.
打他 打他
Do it! Do it!
听着 小伙
Listen, son...
如果你不起诉他们
If you don't press charges...
我就无法防止这些事再次发生
...I can't stop this from happening.
明白吗
Understand?
你不知道
You don't even know.
- 哦 我不懂吗  - 不懂
- Oh I don't?  - Nu-uh.
你认为这是最近才有的吗 小孩儿
You think all this just started, boy?
- 我不是小孩儿  - 你当然不是
- I ain't no boy.  - The hell you ain't.
如果你是个成年男人
If you were a man
你旁边就应该坐着其他四个蠢货了
there'd be four other knuckleheads sittin' right next to you.
你一点都不明白
You don't even know.
听着 小伙子 听着
Listen, son, listen.
听我说
Listen.
我不怪你
I'm not blaming you... I'm not.
我知道这很难
I know it's hard.
相信我
Believe me.
我不是不尊重你的勇敢
I'm not trying to disrespect your struggle.
我只是想让你知道
I just need you to know...
好吧 集中注意力
All right, all right. Stay focused.
嘿 奇伦
Hey... hey, chiron!
放开我
Get the fuck off me, niggas!
Get the fuck off me!
不要看着我
Don't look at me!
- 你好 哥们  - 哟 最近怎么样 老兄
- Hello, homie?  - Yo, what's good with you, b?
看上谁了
vibing, vibing?
- 什么  - 你是不是看上谁了
- What's that?  - You vibin'?
- 我正在尽力  - 尽力
- I'm trying to.  - Trying to?
那你的马子呢
So where the hos at?
老兄 你微笑的样子
Nigga, you smiling and shit
装的跟不知道我在说啥一样
like you don't know what the fuck I'm talking about.
你马子呢 老兄
Where the hos at, nigga?
我不知道 你说呢
I don't know. You tell me.
那个街角住着一个漂亮姑娘
There's this bitch that stay down the corner.
名字叫啥
What's her name?
- 阿佛罗德西亚  - 你编的吧
- Afrodesia.  - You making that up.
我不信你
I don't believe you.
我从没见过你和哪个女的在一起 我不信你
I ain't never seen you with no bitch, I don't believe you.
- 她的名字阿佛罗德西亚  - 她在哪
- Her name afrodesia.  - Her name afrodesia? Where she at?
- 她只在夜间出没  - 好吧
- She only come out at night.  - Okay.
- 是啊  - 嗯
- Yeah.  - Okay.
三. 小黑
钱少了 特拉维斯
You short, Travis.
- 等等 什么  - 剩下那部分钱呢
- Wait, what?  - Where the rest of the roll?
都在这了
It's all there.
你也许觉得我磕嗨了
I mean you might think I tripping,
我给你的时候一定是齐的
when I handed it to you it was all there.
没事
It's a'ight.
如果都在这了 那你数数吧 特拉维斯
If it's all there then count that shit then, trav.
如果都在这儿 数数吧
Count it. If it's all there.
让开 你挡着我了
Move, you're in my spot.
让开
Move.
把我的钱拿过来
Give me my fucking money.
你是说我骗你咯
You sayin' I'm a liar?
好吧
All right.
我并没这么说
I ain't say that.
我告诉你数数少了多少 你说没少
I told you to count what's off and you said it wasn't.
那你就是在说我在说谎咯
That's you calling me a liar.
我只是告诉你
Nah, all I did was tell you that...
你说什么
you-you did what?
我他妈跟你开玩笑的
I'm just fucking with you.
数得没错
Count good.
做得也没错
Did real good.
给
Here.
做这一行 如果忍受不了别人耍你
Can't be on the corner if you can't take a nigga
你很难立足的 懂我吧
just fuckin' with you, you feel me?
嗯
Yeah.
奇伦 妈妈来电话啦
Chiron, this your mama.
我知道很晚了
I know it's late but...
但我猜你从不早睡
...I figured you ain't never been one much for sleep.
亚特兰大没那么大吧
Atlanta ain't but so big...
我还是希望 你能时不时回来看看妈妈
...seemin' me you come see your mama from time to time.
做个好梦 宝贝
Hope you gettin' some rest, baby.
希望不久后你能回来
Hope you come by soon.
妈 已经太晚了
Ma, it's late.
我明天就去看你 我保证
I'll be there tomorrow, I promise.
嘿
Hello?
嘿 小黑
Hey black,
嗯 我是说 奇伦
I mean... chiron.
你好 老兄 我是凯文
What's up, man. This... this Kevin.
你在吗
You there?
嗯
Yeah...
很久不见了 对吧
Long time, no see, right?
老兄 我跟特瑞莎要了你的电话
Man, I had to ask Teresa for your number, and...
等等 老兄 你还记得我吧
Hold on, man. You do-you do remember me, right?
是啊 我记得
Yeah, I do.
真是过去好久了
Been a while.
是啊是啊 老兄
Yeah. Yeah, it has, man.
所以 嗯 你现在在哪
So, uh, where you at now, man?
佐治亚
Georgia.
亚特兰大
Atlanta.
我从那之后就一直在这里了
I've been up here ever since...
嗯 嗯 我听说了
Yeah. Yeah, man, that's what I heard.
是啊
Yeah.
嘿 老兄 我对之前发生的事情很抱歉
Hey, man, I'm sorry about all that...
那些不应该发生的破事 抱歉
All that... Shit what went down... chiron.
我是混蛋 真的
Real shit, dawg, I am.
所以
So, uh...
你现在在做什么
...what you doin' up there, man?
没啥 都是
Not much. Just...
麻烦事
...just trouble.
奇伦总爱惹麻烦啊
Chiron and trouble always found a way.
是啊 差不多吧
Yeah... something like that.
你呢
What about you?
我
Me?
我是个厨子
I'm a cook, man.
你 你当厨子了
Y-y-you a cook?
是啊
Yeah, buddy.
我之前被派去做一些愚蠢的活计
Man, I got sent up for some stupid shit-
就像之前一样
the same stupid shit we always get sent up for.
他们把我分配到厨房
They put me on the kitchen line, man,
我觉得还不错
and I kinda took to it.
不管怎么说 我只
Anyway, man, I just...
我只是很想你
I just thought about you, man. I...
这里有个点唱机
We got this jukebox in here and, uh...
有人点歌 它就会播放
...and folks come by and play they songs,
点唱机里的唱片
that's the music we get in here...
有一首歌
This dude, man...
让我想起了你
...just reminded me of you.
所以
So, uh...
嘿 如果你什么时候来城里 记得来和我打招呼
Hey man, if you ever come to town, man, you come holla at me.
我可以给你做点什么吃
I'll cook you somethin'.
也许
Maybe...
也许可以给你点那首歌
Maybe play that song for you.
好啦 老兄 好好睡吧
All right man, um... You be easy, all right?
你最近怎么样
How you been?
我很好啊
I'm all right.
还是睡不着
I ain't sleepin'.
为什么呢
Why not?
- 嗯 如果你知道  - 做恶梦
- Right. If you knew you'd...  - Bad dreamin'.
还是吗
Still?
你都没尝试过跟谁说说
You ever thought about talking about it with somebody?
甚至不需要是一个心理顾问
Maybe not even a counsellor.
也许可以跟你妈妈说说
Maybe somebody like your mama?
嗯
Yeah...
嗯 我也觉得这么说挺好笑的
Yeah, it sound funny to me too.
你和特瑞莎聊过了吗
You talk to Teresa?
嗯
Yeah.
她怎么样
How she doing?
很好
Good.
“很好”
"Good."
妈 你打算什么时候回家
When you go home, ma?
家
Home?
这里就是家 你知道
This is home. You know...
我是说 他们愿意留下我工作
I mean, they allowing me to stay and work
多久都行 我觉得
as long as I like. I figure...
能帮帮别人也是好事
...might as well help other folks.
让我不惹麻烦
Keep myself out of trouble.
挺好的 妈
That's good, mama.
是啊
Yeah.
是啊 我也这么想
Yeah, I think it is too.
真的
I really do.
你还在街上做生意吗
So, you still in them streets?
你大老远跑去佐治亚
Didn't come all the way the hell to Georgia
却干了同样龌龊的勾当
to have you fallin' in the same shit,
- 奇伦  - 我要走了 要走了
- chiron.  - Im'ma go. Im'ma go...
不 不不不 你听着
no, no, no, no, you gon' listen!
听你的吗 妈妈
To who, ma? Huh?
听你的吗
To you?
真的假的
Really, though?
拜托
Please...
我是个废物
I messed up.
我曾经毁灭了生活中的一切
I fucked it all the way up.
我知道
I know that.
但是你不要走我的老路啊 宝贝
But yo' heart ain't gotta be black like mine, baby.
我爱你 奇伦
I love you, chiron.
真的
I do.
我爱你 宝贝
I love you, baby.
但是你不爱我也没关系
But you ain't gotta love me.
上帝知道我没有在你需要的时候给你我的爱
Lord knows I did not have love for you when you needed it,
我知道
I know that.
所以你不爱我没关系
So you ain't gotta love me...
但你要知道我爱你
...but you gon' know that I love you.
听到了
You hear?
你听见了吗 奇伦
You hear me, chiron?
听见了 妈妈
I hear you, mama.
我来
Here.
我很抱歉 宝贝
I'm sorry, baby.
我非常抱歉
I'm so sorry.
过来 妈妈
Come here, mama.
请稍等
Be right with you.
两位吃的好吗
How y'all doin'?
好吗 那很好
Good? All right.
我把这些收拾了
I'll take these.
一会回来把账单给您
I'll be right back with your check.
一会儿来招待您
Be right with you, boss,
让我收拾一下
just let me get this out the way.
好了
All right...
好了先生 您要点什么
All right, man, how you doing tonight?
我能为您
What can I get you...
奇伦
chiron?
天 老兄 你怎么不说话
Damn man, why you ain't say nothin'?
你好吗 凯文
'Sup, kev?
哎呀 老兄
Damn, man,what...
你在这里做什么
what you doing down here?
我是说
I mean...
嘿
hey, hey...
你来了 这是最重要的事情
You here now, man, that's all that matter.
又来了 只会点头啊 老伙计
There go that damn noddin' again, man,
你真是一点都没变
you ain't-you ain't changed one damn bit.
你现在还是不能一次说三个字以上吗
You still can't say more than three words at a time, huh?
你说过要为我做点吃的
Said you was gon' cook for me,
这我还是会说的
I know how to say that.
是啊 我的确说过 对吧
Yeah, I did say that, didn't I?
看你这身材可不缺吃的
Don't look like your ass been missing no meals.
是啊
Yeah.
没事 我来弄点吃的 你坐吧
But I got you, man. Sit down.
坐下 老兄 你想要点啥
Sit down, man. What you want?
你可以点菜单上的
You can order off the menu if you want to, or...
或者来试试我的主厨特色菜
Hey... I could just hit you with that chef's special.
嗯
Yeah.
没问题 凯龙
We here, chiron.
一份主厨特色菜 马上就来
One chef's special... Coming right up.
主厨特色菜来了
Chef's special.
哦 所以你现在是古巴主厨咯
Oh, so you Cuban now?
只是在厨艺风格上而已
Only in the kitchen, papi.
坐下吧
Yo, sit down, man.
或者你想站着吃
Or are you gon' eat standin' up?
想喝点什么吗
You want a drink?
不了 我不喝
Nah, I don't drink.
真是十年没见的样子
Nigga I ain't seen you in like a decade,
你必须跟我喝两杯
you gon' drink with me.
够了够了 你在干嘛
Nah, bruh, nah! What you doing, man?
欢迎回来 老兄
Welcome back, bruh.
我还以为你说你不喝呢
Damn, bother, I thought you said you didn't drink...
尝不出酒的味道 不敢多喝
Can't really taste it so I don't mess with it.
- 我看见了 我看见了  - 什么啊
- I saw that. I saw that.  - What? What?
你一点都不想浪费 特别好吃吧
You don't wanna waste none of that, do you? It tastes good.
得了吧 老哥 还不错吧
Chill out, man. It's straight.
- 说什么  - 还不错
- Say what?  - It's straight.
还不错
It's straight.
兄弟 怎么也比盒饭好吃吧
Man, please, it's better than chef boyardee, ain't it?
得了吧
Chill out, bruh.
我煮的意面都是硬的
My spaghetti-o's go hard, man.
嘿 慢慢吃
Hey, eat your dinner, man.
慢慢吃
Eat your dinner.
再喝点吗 乔治先生
Got it, Mr. George?
我马上回来
I'll be back.
嘿兄弟 你记得萨蔓莎吗
Hey man, you... You remember Samantha?
漂亮的萨蔓莎
Fine-ass Samantha.
是 我记得她
Yeah, I remember her.
嗯
Yeah?
看看
Check this out.
小凯文
Kevin Jr.
我和萨蔓莎的儿子
Me and Samantha, man.
我们很早就有了他
We had him young, too young.
老兄 进监狱之后生活太艰难
Man, when I got locked up, man, that shit was hard.
我再也回不去原来的街区了
Wasn't no way I could go back the streets, man.
回不去了
Not after this.
- 你们还在一起吗  - 我和萨蔓莎吗
- Y'all still down?  - Me and Sam?
没有 我的意思是
Nah. I mean...
我们挺好的
...we cool.
你知道的 因为小孩子我们不得不这样 但
We gotta be, you know, 'cause of li'l man, but...
只不过不是从前那样了
...nah, not like that, man.
你呢 兄弟
What about you, bruh?
我吗
What about me?
跟我说说吧
Nigga... tell me somethin'.
你在做什么
I mean, what you doin'?
和谁在一起
Who you doin'?
说吧
Man, come on now.
我在厨房忙前忙后
I've been back there in that kitchen, man,
给你做菜
and cooked for your ass and everything, man, hey,
吃人家的嘴软
these grandma rules, man.
拿人家的手短
You know the deal.
吃饱喝足了 该说说了
Your ass eat, your ass speak.
好吧 那我就直说了
All right, straight up?
说吧 直接说
Yeah, nigga, straight up.
我在贩毒
I'm trappin'.
什么
What?
嗯
Yeah.
因为打了那个男孩
When they sent me to Atlanta,
他们送我到亚特兰大的少管所
put me straight into juvie for beatin' the old boy.
在那里我遇到一个人
Met this dude in there.
我出来以后 他让我上街卖毒品
When I come out, he put me on the block.
后来我混得风生水起
Did good at it and rose up.
就是这样
It is what it is.
胡说
Bullshit, man.
不应如此
That ain't what it is.
那不是你 奇伦
That ain't you, chiron.
你又不了解我
Nigga, you don't know me.
我不了解你吗
I don't know you?
这是您的小票
There you are.
二十四点五美元
$24.50.
你为什么要戴金牙
Why you got them damn fronts, man?
为什么给我打电话
Why'd you call me?
什么
What?
我问你为什么打电话给我
Why did you call me?
我告诉过你的
I told you, man...
- 有个男人走进来  - 说重点
- ...dude came in...  - Yeah, yeah, yeah...
他放了首歌
He played this song, man...
这是你的车吗
This you?
你说贩毒还真不是开玩笑说说的啊
You wasn't playin' 'bout them traps, huh.
开始飙车了吗
Ride dirty, huh?
差不多吧
Something like that.
你怎么上下班
So how you be in to work?
坐公交
Bus.
黑车
Jitney.
有时当我带着小凯文的时候
Sometimes Samantha shoot me out there
萨曼塔会来接我
when I got li'l kev.
在迈阿密没车的日子简直无法想象
I can't picture bein' in Miami with no car.
- 这倒是真的  - 我想也是
- Man, it's real out here.  - Yeah, I bet.
这里天气又热 车又慢 还特别堵
Real hot, real slow, and real busted.
感觉自己像个窝囊废
Shot me like a duck out here, man.
你说什么
This nigga said "A duck."
- 你喝高了吧  - 你知道我在做什么
- Yeah, you on one.  - You know what I'm doin'.
我就是有点累了
Nah, I'm just tired, bruh.
谢谢你载我
Hey man, bet on the ride, though.
- 没事  - 很感激你
- Yeah.  - Appreciate it.
不用客气
Yeah, man.
总不能让你坐黑车吧
Can't have yo ass on no jitney.
奇伦
So chiron...
你那样看着我干嘛
What-what you looking at me like that for?
兄弟 告诉我 你为什么突然开车过来
What man, come on, you just drove down here?
嗯
Yeah.
还是说你嗑嗨了
Like you was just- you was just on one...
就开上高速路吗
...and you hit the highway?
是的
Yeah.
那你今晚在哪里过夜
So where you got' stay tonight, man?
- 当心  - 我看着你的
- Watch that shit.  - I got you.
就是这里了
This the spot.
进来吧 就当是自己家一样
Come on in. Get yourself at home.
- 挺不错  - 等我一下 我去换衣服
- This is real, man.  - I'm just... get out of this real quick.
你还好吗
You a'ight?
还好 就是有点头疼
Yeah, no, I just got a little headache.
你还真是不胜酒力
Man, you a lightweight.
是你倒的酒
Nah, you was pouring that mug. You was pouring it.
- 我尝不出味道  - 别说了
- "I can't taste this".  - Chill out, man.
- 我们喝了得有三瓶吧  - 对 三瓶
- We had like three bottles.  - Yeah, three bottles.
我给你沏点绿茶吧
I'll make you some green tea, man, come on.
我才不喝那种东西
I won't be drinking that shit either, man.
- 那你要喝什么  - 水
- What do you drink?  - Water.
你是谁
Who is you, man?
谁 我吗
Who, me?
对 你
Yeah, nigga. You.
我是说 你的金牙
I'm saying, man, them fronts.
那辆车
That car.
你到底是谁 奇伦
Who is you, chiron?
我在做自己
I'm me, man.
我没有要做别人啊
I ain't tryin' to be nothin' else.
好吧 那你现在很厉害啊
Oh, okay. So you hard now?
- 我没那么说  - 那是怎样
- I ain't say that.  - Well then what?
嘿 我不是在说你不好 只是
Hey, hey, hey, I ain't tryin' to hem you up, man, it's just...
有太久没见你了
I ain't seen you in a minute and...
你与我想象中不太一样
...it's not what I expected.
那你想象的是怎样的我
Well what did you expect?
你还记得
You remember...
上一次我见到你的时候吗
You remember the last time I saw you?
太久了 我尽量不去想
For a long time, tried not to remember.
试着忘掉过去的种种
Tried to forget all those times.
好吧
Yeah.
我来到亚特兰大
When we got to Atlanta...
开始了新的生活
...I started over.
白手起家
Built myself from the ground up.
变得强大起来
Built myself hard.
- 你怎么样  - 我吗
- What about you? You...  - me?
我根本不值一提
I wasn't never really worth shit.
只是浑浑噩噩地活着
Just kept on, man.
从未实现过心中所想
Never really did anything I actually wanted to do.
我能做的
It was all I could do was
就是活成别人所想的样子
to do what folks thought I should be doing.
我从来没真正做自己
I wasn't never really myself.
现在呢
And now?
现在
Now?
如今
Now, man...
我有了小凯文
...now I got li'l kev.
做着这份工作
Got this job.
十八个月的实习期
Another 18 months of probation.
真实无比
That 's some real shit, man.
这就是我的人生
Nah, man. It's a life.
你知道吗
You know?
我从来没经历过这样的生活
I ain't never had that before.
现在的我
Like...
疲于奔命
Like, I'm tired as hell right now, man,
挣着这点小钱
and I ain't making more than shoe money, but...
但是我已经不再烦恼了
...I ain't got no worries, man.
我是说以前的种种烦恼
Not them kind what I had before.
这是真实的生活
That's that real shit.
就像鲍勃・马利说过的那样
That's that Bob Marley shit, nigga.
这一生只有你抚摸过我
You the only man that's ever touched me.
只有你一个
You're the only one.
从那以后我也没再碰过别人
I haven't really touched anyone, since.
月光男孩